Rishab Kaul

Email: rishabh.kaul93@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rishab-kaul-625a014a

Mobile: +91-9953010037

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Commercially astute multi-faceted management professional with experience in business development/account management aims to build a career in consulting by constantly contributing toward the organization's growth with strong determination and hard work by offering excellent skills in all aspects of consulting, account management, marketing mix, and commercial awareness. Adept at developing critical solutions while standardizing and refining existing techniques and procedures. In addition, instrumental in directing teams, cooperating across functions to complete projects and fulfill important deadlines, and bringing a creative approach to problem-solving with a record of success in developing strategies, and solutions that have increased revenue growth. Recognized for being well-versed in communication and skilled strategist/negotiator with the ability to build relationships with key personnel.

EDUCATION

Loughborough University, United Kingdom, September 2019–September 2021 MBA (Master of Business Administration) passed with merit (2:1).

Key modules: Business Analytics, Strategic Marketing, Accounting and Performance Management, Corporate Finance, Management of Human Resources, Managing Innovation, Managing Global Firms, Global Outsourcing and Offshoring, Leading Strategic Change, etc.

Advance Certificate Course in Marketing, Certified by A.I.M.A (ALL INDIA MANAGEMENT ASSOCIATION) (2017)

Key Modules: Marketing of Services, Internet/Digital Marketing, Product Management, Customer Relationship Management.

GALGOTIA'S UNIVERSITY, Greater Noida, UP, September 2011- May 2015 Bachelor of Technology (EEE) awarded with 7.06 CGPA.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Customer Service Crew (Part-Time), Loughborough, Leicestershire, UK October 2019-March 20

McDonald's.

- Resolved product or service issues by clarifying the customer's complaint, finding the root cause of the problem, and selecting and conveying the best solution to the problem. accelerating the process of rectification or adjustment; following up to secure a satisfactory resolution
- Responsible for taking customer orders in accordance with workplace ethics. This entails
 asking and confirming the food items chosen by consumers, then running cash registers to
 handle payment.
- Responded to incoming consumer questions in person, and via phone in a timely and professional manner.

Key Account Manager, Delhi, India, December 2015 – August 2019 M/s Kaul Brother.

- Helped in the achievement of EBITDA targets, through the control of costs.
- Enhanced customer experience by analyzing customer buying behavior, regularly attending fairs and developing products accordingly.
- Nurtured relationships with key accounts by continuously proposing solutions that meet their objectives within the time frame.
- Identified new markets for kitchenware products & started exports to Saudi Arabia and the USA. Collaborated extensively with overseas sales representatives to ensure that clients' needs were fulfilled or surpassed.
- Built & maintained a strategic local relationship with carriers and vendors by taking them on board in every decision to ensure optimal competitive costs and services.
- Managed all export logistics and paperwork efforts for a firm.
- Actively monitored and analyzed consumer, market, and competition activities to identify new upcoming trends to create business growth opportunities.

Content Writer, Gurugram, Haryana, India, July 2015 – November 2015 Publicis Sapient

- Worked closely with client teams to hone a point of view that excites, educates, and engages their customers.
- Contributed "HTML" knowledge for developing websites for client "John Deere".
- Prepared well-structured drafts using Content Management System.
- Wrote and edited content using HTML in different languages.

SKILLS

- Writing and Communication: Able to communicate in (HINDI, ENGLISH, & PUNJABI) in both ways verbally and on paper with a trait of being an empathic listener & persuasive speaker.
- **Teamwork:** Excellent at working in a team. Previously worked on a kitchenware product for a client where some changes in products were done through the collective effort of the team and this change led to 2X growth in sales of that product.
- **Organizational Skill:** Able to manage time effectively and prioritize tasks in line with the needs of the business. Proven history of delivering the consignment to importers on time.
- Commercial Awareness: An active follower of business trends with appropriate commercial awareness. Used this skill to start "ESMA" certification for kitchenware products, especially for UAE-based customers.
- **Customer Service:** Able to give effective service through being calm, empathic, and an effective listener during a crisis. Previously provided effective customer service to one of "M/s Kaul Brother's" buyers on the unfortunate sinking of consignment.
- **MS Office:** Performed sales forecasting using time series decomposition & regression analysis methods in MS Excel.
- **Critical Thinking:** Gathered information and understood the client's need by assessing multiple options before arriving at the aspired solutions.
- Macro & Micro Environmental Analysis: Quantified business possibilities to consolidate successful business plans and identified important organizational strengths and weaknesses related to project planning. Moreover, Increased sales by 50% over two years by doing a SWOT analysis for kitchenware products.